Alright.
>> Yeah.
No. I'm I'm happy to see that you guys are testing the waters here because
the Zoom thing is driving everyone nuts.
This is good.
>> Okay. I'll make this very simple.
So we brought three contractors,
paving contractors to the transfer station to get an idea of what it's gonna cost
so I don't have a full breakdown. But I sat down with Pat, so we went through the numbers.
Roughly 5,000
of that is the cost to bring somebody in with the rototiller
or to peel
the existing pavement up and
haul it off to get disposed of.
So there's about a day and a half labor, he thinks, in grading it properly
to drain. That's presuming public works puts in
a double basin ahead of time before they get there. Could we have public works just to peel it up with the
odor?
I'm just saying if it's $5, and we've got disposal right behind it, can we?
No.
Mean, when we peel it up, we put it in a truck
I mean, we could if if you wanna pursue that option.
I don't I mean, they've certainly peeled up all the asphalt that's
that's been removed so far. You know, they peeled up and recycled it. They can't
It just to me, the the time and effort of peeling it up versus the time and effort of just grinding it up and adding it right to the material,
it's about a wash, I think.
>> I just thought I was thinking $5 versus, what, 1,600 for a day's labor for a polyp arts. Yeah. How do you know it's a wash?
>> Well, because
so one of the contractors
gave me a a cost assuming it was gonna be ground up, and the other one gave me a cost
>> with them grinding it up versus them peeling it up and removing it. Is there an advantage to that? I mean, given that they have to regrade it anyways?
>> To grinding it up? Yeah. You just end up with, you know, a tiny little bit more material.
No. No. They would just be grinding it into the the existing sub base
and using that as part of the sub base. K. Okay.
Now same thing when you recycle or reclaim the road. You just basically grind up the first
Right. I mean, honestly, the the base,
>> I
also had another thought.
Looking at that, whether or not we should be
pouring concrete slabs
over the top of those blocks
to take up some of the other issues that we talked about as far as being able to anchor to areas and things like that. Would it make sense to look at slabbing that?
>> You know, there's always
part of what I was trying to do, frankly, is,
>> you know, stay somewhat within the budget that we had allocated. I'm not criticizing what was done. I'm asking if you think that that would be a viable solution to address some of the issues that we're gonna have otherwise with putting the correct railing. I
>> mean, I think I worked with Public Works to come up with a solution for the railing that they're happy with and I'm happy with. So we have a solution right now? So we have a solution. We are going to have to pour
on the side with the compactors.
We are going to have to pour
some small pads too bold to,
>> you know, where it dips down. We're thinking about the same thing in some way. I guess I was just thinking about bigger pads
and maybe it'd be more cumbersome,
you know, and that would also change. I'm just really worried about
compaction.
I didn't see the back film happening,
whether or not they were walking whether or not they were really back
compacted really well because settling against a wall with drainage is always an issue.
So
and we haven't had that up very long. We haven't had a lot of rain this summer.
You know, available to you. And that doesn't sound like much, but if you wanna keep grass green,
that's a lot of water.
You give them the location of that. Well, I'm guessing it's not We're gonna talk to the
>> scope of the project,
you know,
can't
whatever the original scope is is what they're funding.
So we couldn't do what we did before, which was
fund the project and then kinda change
pretty considerably considerably what what we we were were doing. Doing. So So
so given those
that circumstance,
I thought probably the most important thing we had or we could fund out of state would either be a roadwork project or a culvert project.
But given
where we are in the planning process for culverts,
I thought it would be better to do a roadwork project.
So my suggestion
is we do
what we were planning on doing anyway,
which is
Long Hill Road from Route 6 to the just past the Bear Swamp Intersection,
and then Shawnee Mill from Route 6
to the intersection of Wales
to be coordinated with the drainage work that we need to do on Shawnee Mill,
and that would basically reconstruct
those road sections.
>> And that would be covered by what? A 100% between a 100% match up and speed.
>> Right. So I have two I put in your packet
cost estimates from that. Mhmm. We have numbers from two different contractors.
Again, we put out an RFP,
but we have pretty solid numbers. Okay.
And that would both doing both of those would be around 265,000.
We could simply tell the contractor to keep rolling up the road till we run out of money. And we won't get an answer on this until the next year, guess. Right? No? No.
For the steep grant, we'll we will know supposedly,
we will know by
want to assess him for his use of the meal.
That's the,
you know
I mean, the question is, do you wanna decide
what is it how how do you wanna proceed from here? I mean, I feel like,